True
yes
Don't throw away your lip balm
Drink it, it looks cold.
thank you
Ah!
It's okay
I'm afraid of getting wet, this is comfortable
I'm uncomfortable
- I'll get something else.
- Huh? No, really...
Ah... sorry
Drink that, you'll catch a cold
What are these pictures?
What are you doing?
who is this?
Who draws a wall painting on a person's face?
What are you doing?
Who put the Byeoksabu pattern on the photo?
I drew it and erased it
This
It's used to chase away ghosts.
You shouldn't draw on people's faces.
I know
You know?
So you deleted everything?
Who said that?
If you erase Byeoksabu, the curse disappears?
If you draw on the face of a living person
Just spitting, ‘Don’t be lucky.’
49 It’s different to draw a dead person who hasn’t passed away.
I'm praying to King Yeomra.
Go to hell grandma
It's a strong curse
You can't erase it
Miss...
So it's not me
You did it to your grandmother?
Photo...
You have to burn it, Gyeonwoo.
What does that look like?
Not a mouse caught in the rain
You said my efforts were in vain, right?
Do you really know where to go to Yeomhwa?
What do you see?
It's an album
Those old photos
Isn’t it pretty, my daughter?
Did you sprain your eye?
Even if you erase it, it won’t disappear
Wishes don't disappear so easily
The desire to harm others
Because a wish is a wish
Somehow
It was strange
my wish is
I've never heard of it before
My wish to live normally with my grandmother is
It never happens
I hope that person's wish will come true
That person...?
Do you know the person who drew this?
Can we meet now?
- What if we meet?
- I have to ask.
Please give me your wish
Perform a purification ceremony
Grandma, go to a nice place when you celebrate the relocation ceremony.
Uh, you don't have to burn this photo.
yes
If you ask me, I might be able to do it.
My request is to kneel down and beg
I won't listen
You know the person who drew this
The shaman who danced with you
That person drew it
The King's Mother called
Mansinbun said
It's a lie, bright red
This damn thing hit the player
Anyone who enters the house
I hit a player who became a sacrifice to evil spirits.
I don't know about you
I'm so close to Yeomhwa.
Why are you so nice to me?
Watching the two of you being swayed by me
Are you having fun or what?
What if
If you're playing with me now
Can I just take a look this once?
grandma photo
It's really precious to me
let me ask you a favor
Cheonji Fairy
My hands are too cold
I'm sorry
And you won't believe it
A shaman named Yeomhwa
I saw you for the first time that day at the abandoned house.
I really don't know
and me
Not you but anyone
Even if it's not a person or a ghost
I don't want to play with it
I don't want to make anyone else cry
Ah
Isn't it delicious?
Oh, how about something like this?
uh?
Well, well...
I feel like shit
Are you hurting me?
So... you just have to do well.
That's what kids like you do
I just enjoy doing it
Are you bragging?
I'm not ashamed
Are you a little shy?
Are you really ashamed of me?
That's why you treat me like this?
What kind of abuse is this!
I...
Huh? see and hear
What? scapular?
I'll go out for a bit
Huh? Hey
Hey, where are you going!
To touch the cowherd
Touch it? why?
Gyeonwoo Bae!
You can't ride backwards!
Oh, sorry.
No matter who sees it
Are you going to meet H, are you?
Write...
I need to see your face too
I hurt you a little when I saw it.
With family members
I guess you're having trouble coordinating.
How many times have I opened this place already?
It'll be over soon
Grandma, let me check.
I wouldn't have just done Byeoksabu.
If it were me
This is...
What are you doing now?
How are you, father?
father?
Permission? Did you receive it?
go back
Please call the shaman.
- What?
- I have something to ask you.
Go back first
I'll contact you when I get back.
Contact...
You won't give it to me
who knows my number
There is only a shaman.
Everyone in this house
You didn't save my number, you're cheating.
But now I can't contact the shaman.
It says the number doesn’t exist
I'm not doing this because of myself.
Because of my grandmother... yes.
How dare you bring up your mother?
If you don't call me
I can't move a single step from here.
I'll just meet the shaman and go.
I can't even reach out to other people
Without even touching it
Even if you talk to me, you won't answer
I promise
Hey, honestly, this is pretty.
So where are you going?
huh? gum?
Ugh, really...
Are you here, pretty fairy?
I picked up Lee Mae Mangyangbu.
It needs to be purified immediately
Why are you picking this up?
Even the shaman who lost his life and the dead who got stabbed
I know both of them.
Then we can purify it
But do you know a shaman who uses Imaemangryangbu?
Why do you know that guy?
How do you know?
It's chloride
It's called Yeomhwa, a shaman with an amulet.
Do you have some guts?
Want me to cleanse the wall part of the photo?
That's it
Grandma did nothing wrong
what are you
Because there was a mistake
Were you born with Sangmun?
There's nothing wrong with you either
Ah, kinda...
Please
Don't you know what my job is?
Misfortune is pouring in upon you
Blocking is the priority
The bad luck that dwells in this family
You take it all, Sangmun?
Is there a reason why your guts got better?
How long has it been since I ate my grandmother?
Are you making your own part yet?
Like this, like this, like this, like this
Right here
Is this right?
That's right
But here
Write it like this, like this...
Like this?
Give it to me, I'll do it
Write, do you know the face of the dead?
Stay still, Seongah has to do it.
I'm sorry
I've used Imaemangryangbu many times.
This is my first time solving it.
Were you such a great person?
Are you telling your new daughter to curse others?
Write it
Before I met my mother
When I lived with my biological parents.
I need to focus
I'm concentrating
I ran just in case, I
Oh Ok-soon, born in Shinmyonyeon
Please pay off this money starting today.
Salary Benefits Ordinance Sabaha
Well done
You're good at it
We'll do the rest because it's sorted out
You're all gone, right?
Go in and get some rest
Okay, take a break.
thank you
purification
Can't we just do it here?
You have to do it inside, it's inside.
What's inside?
It doesn't suit Sangmoon.
It's like a useless hope
key
I don't think I have it on my body.
Where are you supposed to be here?
I found it
Why are you so mean?
- What is it?
- Well, Gyeonwoo...
It's not a phrase
I'm a shaman
You gave it to me, right?
Isn't it?
I have it well
Don't ever lose it
Let's go out, right?
Let's go out and talk
Why?
I don’t want to go out?
Good
Hey Gyeonwoo
Would you like to go out for a moment?
I'm curious
What are you going to talk about?
Are you even giving your child away?
just
Something to talk about between shamans
It seems like an interesting story, but what should I do?
I want to listen to it with Sangmoon.
Do you want to purify together? Do you want to ride alone?
I'll just stay here
tell me, it's okay
I guess bullying people is something you’re good at?
Well, okay
I've never bothered anyone much.
I mainly manage things other than people.
That's good
I’m also good at handling non-human things.
Oh my, be scared.
Let's go out, yeah
Are you going to keep doing that?
no
You keep doing that, what?
Ah!
Did you suddenly go crazy?
Why are you touching that dirty thing with your bare hands?
No way
No?
Isn't that what I think?
No, that's not...
Huh?
No matter how unpleasant the chlorine is, that’s true.
What should I do to get back my life with revenge?
Did you get permission to give me your body?
The general said it was okay to do it?
He's going to punish you.
Fair words!
That great rope
They say they'll use it for something mean, like a curse.
Of course the general is pissed
So I decided to take my compensation.
What?
Japanese kids did that
If you curse, there will be two graves
One opponent's grave, one mine
To open the Chloride Tomb
You should open my grave too, won't you?
fat?
I went to the charnel house.
I have already taken care of the imamangryangbu issue.
Grandma, don’t make a fuss on the way to the underworld.
I'll do my best
Why don't we stop here?
Are you making such a fuss just to say that?
Because it's not just
People are different from animals.
There is a thing called heart
If you hit your mom, it only hurts her.
If you hit a child in front of his mother
Mom and baby are both sick, right?
Mom hurts more
Rather than hurting your body
It hurts more to be hurt
So?
Grandma hit Gyeonwoo because it hurts
Gyeonwoo hit his grandmother because she was in pain.
You've been bothering me so much until now, right?
You have no intention of cleaning up the photos anyway, right?
You're planning to burn it all
Why do you think that?
A shaman who offers to purify
Without purified water, incense, or candles
Are you ready to complain?
Are you the only shaman?
I am also a shaman
quite a bit
Is it true what Seongah said?
really
from the beginning
Have you ever thought about cleaning up the photos?
What do you think I did?
If you're going to burn it anyway, this is better.
Rather than burning it with those dirty hands
If that's what you mean
I have nothing to do
I have to go
But Sangmoon
The hand held to avoid chlorine
Why is it a Miwol-dong baby?
Your life too
It's pathetic
Until now, Gyeonherd continues
Did you call it Sangmun?
Sang-moon died not long ago.
It's a word used when calling a ghost.
Gyeonwoo is alive and well.
Why is it called Sangmun? Why!
Why on earth...
It's alive
I beg you
Are you crazy?
Not to me, but to the Lord who gave me my body.
I thought you didn’t know?
Instead of giving me a body, I'm holding on to evil spirits
I probably didn't have any intention of purifying it.
Even if I tried, I failed.
I recognized Gyeonwoo from the time he called me Sangmun.
How many bad things have you done?
The soul vessel is breaking.
So?
I have to pray to the god who gave me my body.
ask me to come back
You can't be a shaman if you're a ghost.
Shut up!
My mouth will be torn apart
What if you organize it?
It's so scary
A shaman with insignificant skills
Are you saying you're next to Gyeonwoo?
If I last two days, it's three to seven days.
At times like this
Don't worry, I'm here
If you see a ghost starting tomorrow
Let's hug it right away, just
You see ghosts
I have to touch it
Yeah
My breathing must be better than I thought, right?
Is Gyeonwoo okay?
It'll be okay
I'm cleaning up outside
Because your alter ego is guarding the house.
Boy, you're working hard
But
Why do I feel so low?
I think I forgot something important.
What is it?
think about it carefully
Oh, I don't know
See what I did wrong again
See you tomorrow
Two days...
You just have to last two days
After just 37 days safely,
Now you don’t have to be associated with a shaman for the rest of your life.
You will be just like everyone else
You'll feel comfortable
Burn that precious photo
I protected my precious grandmother.
Don't listen to that guy.
You're not weak, you're strong enough
just hate me
Even if I were you
I think he really hated the shaman.
I'm sorry
What I mean is that you hate me
Even if it's a lie, it hurts
You should hate me, you idiot.
Something like this
Are you trying to stop me with something like this?
just one person
If only one person is caught
Aren't you an evil spirit?
just one person
If only one person is caught...
If this happens
If you do this quickly
Will you be able to do it quickly?
Have a nice day
By giving my body
Welcome
Uh, hey
Boy, it was disinfected, huh?
It can't be repeated
Kid...
I'll take care of it...
Would you like to see me for a moment?
You too
Yes!
Don’t you practice saengyun?
You two haven't even touched each other yet?
I'll do it now, really I...
I'll do it right now
I'm sorry
Today too
Yesterday too
If I had stayed still, I would have been sorry tomorrow too.
Question, what about Seong-ah?
Seongah didn’t do it either.
he did it
You did very well
thank you
I heard you did everything for me?
For such a crappy thing
Can't waste your precious time
So
What is a real psychic photo here?
Uh...
With this
This
As expected, I have this
I really thought it was a ghost
no
Not that, here
I'm standing here
oh
W, here?
You are truly a mysterious people.
It's cool
I don't have time
Ah, I'm annoyed, I'm annoyed
this traitor
get out of the way, get in the way
- Help me
- Huh?
I want to take psychic photos
Uh, uh...
Psychic photo?
Uh...
here
Take a picture anywhere
Is it just a psychic photo?
But what kind of ghost is this?
Are you stuck on the floor like this?
Because it's a dog
Oh...
dog ghost
Why?
Fighting
You know you’re on a different team than me, right?
hey
here, here
here, here, here
Ah...
Ah, now
now
Teacher!
Hey, it's foul here, foul!
- No, teacher!
- Seongya
uh
one person
Uh, no, no, no.
Ah, uh, one, one
Oh!
Ah, two
one animal and one person
Huh?
Why, why is that so?
No, sorry, sorry
Mmm, cute, our luck
Oh my gosh
fairy, fairy
Huh?
uh
Um...
Why?
Musicless ghost?
Assi, A.C.
Hey, hey!
Teacher foul! Boy foul! I keep...
Huh? class president
I'm sick so I'll leave early
Huh?
Hey, hey, if you do that, you’ll be leaving early without permission!
Seong-ah, why is he like that?
Wow, it didn't look painful.
It didn't even look good
Take it, Seong-ah has something to say.
Seongah?
- Uh, it's me.
- Hey, Pyoho
I just use human amulets whenever I have time.
I'm sticking with you no matter what
Why, why, huh?
Uh, yeah
Don't worry, get some rest, yeah
As expected
Is this a situation where you desperately need my help?
No, it's not like that, it's just...
You look free?
You must have a lot of time?
Do your best on performance evaluation
Don't make the boss angry
He's angry 24 hours a day anyway.
Seongah is also worried for no reason.
you are loud
You can do it all today, right? Performance evaluation?
Until today?
I have archery practice in the evening?
Oh, really?
Write it down, then both of you until tomorrow morning.
All night!
Stay up all night?
- Hey, spending the night together?
- Yes
You are a genius, Hyeri.
I'll stay up all night, I'll definitely stay up all night!
Let's go all night, my friend.
Wait, what's wrong?
Smells like sweat, dirty
Your face is red.
It got uglier
what?
Oh, my, my! Wow!
This
There are egg ghosts all over the neighborhood.
It's so disgusting, I'm dying.
Egg ghost...
So, if you don’t go home, you can return home.
Normally it's not that harmful...
If we were to be mobbed like that
Things change.
The owner who will find a new face
It means it will show up soon
The birth of an evil spirit
They are the first ones to congratulate
A guy who will become an evil spirit
It's so obvious who he is
He must be the one whose lungs are sealed.
Let's go there first.
yes
Ah, I don't want to go, ah!
It's chlorine
you are so crazy
First of all, do what you can right now.
Babies who are nothing
I'm fussing
Just really, really!
Don’t leave me alone!
Oh my, be scared.
What do we do now?
That one
I need to find the puppet's head.
If you don't remove the spell placed on the doll,
Ghosts will continue to gather
Rumors of evil spirits appearing
Because my hair grows
Yeah, you have to find the head first.
Alright, let's find the head.
But
Somehow, in this direction, the fairy of heaven and earth is better than the general.
You think you know better?
Same with Imaemangyangbu?
Do you think it's worth buying?
And it flutters needlessly, flutters again
That's because I'm curious, because there's a question mark
Because there was a question mark
Oh, find it quickly.
- Gyeonwoo.
- Huh?
The weight is a bit strange, this thing
Take a look
Look look
- Come
-What's strange?
Write, I don’t know.
Is it not centered?
a little?
uh? Isn't it strange?
Write, ah...
Give it a try
- It's okay, it's okay...
- are you okay?
are you okay?
Oh, that would be weird, right? Kid...
Archery was originally like that.
Was it a sport with a lot of skinship?
- uh?
- yes?
motorcycle!
bicycle!
Hey...
Lear car!
Let go
It's dangerous!
Ha, what a dangerous world it is.
Isn’t that right, Gyeonwoo?
Really
Hey, Gyeonwoo!
Grandpa, I will help you.
- Me too.
- One, two, one, two
- Hey
- Huh?
why?
Ah, it's done.
But there is Seong-ah
Huh? Seongah?
Seonga why?
Why is Seong-ah suddenly?
It's nothing
Is it him?
oh! Oh, it's him, hey!
Wow, gross! Ugh!
Bring it quickly and burn it.
It's okay to burn it
Rumors should be covered with rumors
Let's spread the word that you won't become an evil spirit.
The ghosts run away as quickly as possible
No, no matter what, it doesn’t hurt, does it?
Why did you draw something like that?
It hurts more if you hesitate
I tried it when I was young
Baby, please work a little harder.
Come alive
cowherd
get out
Get out!
Okay, okay.
I'm going out, I'm going out, I'm going out
sleep well, yeah
I have a question.
ask
We danced together back then
Do you know the shaman?
Are you close?
Miwol-dong baby shaman
That was the first time I actually saw it too.
He'll have to live a long time too.
Because when you die, you’ll go to hell like me.
8 year old baby shaman
Seongah’s morning is better than other friends’
It starts a little early
Roses have bloomed
here
That's right
My daughter got a rose tattoo there.
Baby
Yes?
Oh, he's twenty now.
Who is the child's father?
Even if I die, I won't open my mouth
Have you ever
Are you pregnant?
How does mom know that?
Do you know that this is Miwol-dong baby shaman?
It also appeared in the documentary People Theater 10 years ago.
It was pretty famous
That's me
Those kind of idiots
I can't touch a lot of money
Can't you use one of the imaemangryangbu properly?
don't cry
You can't cry
mom and dad like it
I won't see ghosts
I can be a good boy
don't abandon me
Don't abandon me...
Kid
Do you want to die in return?
What are you talking about like that?
It's nothing
You can do anything.
Ah, then when I was in middle school
It was your first time going to school, right?
People who were victimized by baby shamans in Miwol-dong
Everyone
Justice is still alive
It's all karma, right?
end
completion
Oh, stop acting strong.
Uh, huh?
Well, what are you doing, you two?
If children can't cry when they should
Adults are upset
I'm upset right now
Cheongseung, don’t be nervous.
Well, good
Hey
Since when have you been friends with Seong-ah?
Are we not close?
Since my freshman year of high school last year
Then before that
Don't you know what I've been doing for a living?
We heard it together
I took the qualification exam in elementary and middle school.
How much have I done wrong to her so far?
Do you think I am a fool?
How many times have I met a shaman?
you touching me
I'm doing it because Seong-ah told me to do it.
What Seongah said to me before
Actually
I even did a cowherd and a cowherd to survive.
If you don't know, you're an idiot.
Do you believe it now?
Is Seong-ah really trying to protect you?
uh
Bae Gyeonwoo
You really just have to wait until tomorrow
You bastard who returns this favor with revenge
My, my, what tomorrow?
It's just that you're a really bad guy
You just need to know, yeah
See you tomorrow, Gyeonwoo
What kind of father are you!
You cheap bastard! uh?
This damn bastard is real!
under! This bastard
Huh? Jinwoong?
You bastard, you bastard
It's a blessing
- Hey
- ask
You can do it, you're lucky
- Ask, ang
- Hey, hey!
I asked loudly
Ask!
what?
- hey!
- Good job.
Seongya
Huh?
Oh, I, I didn't do anything.
Gyeonwoo, it’s true.
Huh? Ah, no...
Well, today is also a group class, right?
Oh my, Park Seong-ah is not sleeping for some reason.
Jinwoong?
Ah, yes
- Yes
- Yeah.
These days, Jinwoong
That was too sincere, wasn't it?
Uh, come on, let’s make a place quickly.
Ah, so
Quickly change your number and move.
Mom, don't contact anyone.
Huh?
Especially don't do this to me, okay?
Oh, it came from that bastard bread!
Mom, if I get caught this time...
I'm dying
I said I knew you, right?
Hey, man!
I won't hit you
Stand there, man!
Hey, Jinwoong Kim!
Hey, man!
Son, are you hiding here?
If you get caught by your father, you will be hunted!
Hey son!
Let's talk to dad, okay?
Wow, wow!
Jinwoong Kim!
uh?
what?
ring?
I'll organize it one last time
we are talking about
In Kant's anthropocentric philosophy
What is the most important thing?
It means thinking with humans in mind.
Machines are not the center, but humans are the center.
Money is not the focus, people are the focus
Because humans are precious
Don't treat people as a means to an end
Why?
huh?
You shouldn't treat people as a means to an end
Don't you understand?
teacher
I'll bring Jinwoong here.
- Uh, where...
- Hey
Are you in here?
Jinwoong?
It doesn't work here
Good luck, you can't go in here.
Save me!
Oh, it really doesn't work.
IC
They say the fairy has now entered the abandoned house.
Save me...
Hey!
Jinwoong, breathe, breathe.
Jinwoong!
Ah, let Jinwoong go!
Shaman, hello?
You should say hello too, right?
If it's going to be like this, then
Takes my breath away
Huh? Hey Gyeonwoo!
You shouldn't do this to people.
The last offering is
I handpicked this
You live
Shall I teach you why it is hell?
You crazy guy, follow me
Why is it Gyeonwoo again?
Because it's easy, he
How many sins have you committed?
Is it completely black like this?
I'll just kill you all!
Was I a person?
Found it